"Britain has been accused
of being behind the plot
to kill Robert Mugabe."
Masuku is being held in the
secure wing of the Chikurubi priso
You want me to break him out?
Masuku has to disappear completely.
What was it you wanted to say?
It can wait.
Why didn't you tell him?
I got everything you asked for.
All legit South African documents.
in the name of a real life
SONOP Inspektir.
You're coming with me.
Am I?
Isn't this a dead end?
Yeah. But it's our way out.
There's been a breach.
I've been compromised.
Get out now. Lieutenant.
that's an order. What about Porter?
(SHOUTING / GUNFIRE)
Radio traffic confirms there has
been a breakout from Chikurubi.
I was hired by British intelligence
to kill Mugabe.
They betrayed me.
They betrayed you too!
Who the fuck do you trust?
Sorry. mate. I only packed for one.
Understandable.
So. what's Plan B?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
It was Colonel Tshuma.
I'm sure of it.
What makes you so certain?
His Elite Guard
were all over the Land Rover.
Makes sense.
Why. something else
you're not sharing with me?
We intercepted Elite Guard
transmissions from Chikurubi.
They were there immediately
after Porter's jail break. "Shit."
I should've got him out myself.
Layla. it was operationally
the right choice.
For Porter or for you?
Listen.
"Shopper this is Lancer. come in."
It's Porter.
Lancer. this is Shopper.
Glad to hear your voice.
I was expecting transport.
Apologies. Papa ordered me home.
Uninvited guests.
Is the 'Ugly Trade' complete?
Change of mission.
Repeat. change of mission.
Prepare exit for two.
He's bringing out Masuku.
tell him he can't.
Explain. Lancer.
Passenger claims his job was
a legitimate UK contract.
Do you understand
what am saying to you? Over.
(DIAL TONE)
Understood.
How long until you reach rendezvous
We fancy a little walk.
With you tomorrow evening.
I'll wait for you. Reconnect 1800?
Copy that. Over and out.
Right.
We need to head for this location.
An exit camp just over the border.
Layla will debrief you there.
Layla?
The same woman who was supposed
to leave the Land Rover. yeah? Yeah
Can you trust her?
It's not her I'm worried about.
I'll call you back.
Masuku claims he was recruited
directly by the British government.
And you believe him?
Right now. sir.
I don't know what to believe.
A bullet in Mugabe's head
might be desirable for some
but the order did not
come from this office.
Well. then that leaves
only two options.
Which are?
Either Masuku's lying.
or he's been set up
to think he was working for us.
Is your man aware
of the consequences of his actions?
There is one other thing. John.
If this goes wrong...
The last bullet's for me.
Yes. sir. Fully.
Danni.
Get me a file on all UK intelligence
liaison for Zimbabwe
over the last five years.
This about Masuku?
Someone's recruited him.
handling him. need to find out wh
Are we looking for a double agent?
Yeah. Check bank records.
Unusual patterns of behaviour.
you know the drill. Sir.
(PHONE RINGS)
Diane?
(ALEX) "Where's Dad?
I need to talk to my dad."
Lexi -
"I need to talk to my dad.
where is he?"
"It's my mum."
What is it?
Nothing.
Let's just stop for a minute.
There's some water in the side pouch
Thanks.
Shit.
We've got trouble.
Bushman. On the ridge.
And scouts with a radio.
Yeah.
Tshuma's men.
Mm-hm.
OK. We need to move.
No. no. That man can tell
how far ahead we are just by
the dent in our footprints.
Hard ground. Keep low.
Lexi.
(CRIES)
Porter.
Let's stay on the tarmac.
no footprints.
OK.
(SHOUTS)
Stop.
This way.
Remind me not
to come your way next time.
(GUNFIRE)
Could be worse.
(HELICOPTER)
It just got worse.
Lancer. this is Shopper. over.
Lancer. this is Shopper. waiting
at home. Do you read me. over?
Here. Cinderella.
Have a look at this.
Not a hope.
That's twice
in my professional career
I've chosen not to kill someone
and lived to regret it.
Was the first an Iraqi kid?
How did you know about that?
Part of the training.
Mistakes to learn from.
Yeah?
What have you brought to the party
apart from being a pain in the ass?
I just swept.
Layla. have you heard from Porter?
"Not so far. sir. I'll keep trying."
OK. Speak soon.
(KNOCKS)
Sir. here's MI6's record of
all intel liaisons to Zimbabwe.
This person caught my interest.
He's been careless.
Harry Curtis. our embassy contact.
His apartment in Jo'burg is paid f
out of his civic service salary.
But we discovered three other
properties purchased by him
under one of his logged aliases.
Alan Shenley.
Did you follow the money?
It wasn't hard.
Shenley has bank accounts
all around the world.
Antigua. Caymans. Liechtenstein.
Five million dollars
we've traced so far.
Where's the money coming from?
Here.
Holmann Trust and Investments?
It's a Swiss bank.
used by Mugabe's ministers.
Get me a flight to Jo'burg tonight.
Sir.
They've got a phone.
Hm.
What do you think?
It's too risky. We move on.
(CHILD) Leave me alone!
(MAN SHOUTS)
(GIRL SCREAMS)
He's gonna rape her.
We do this quietly.
I'll cover the house.
Stop it. no!
Stop it!
No. stop it!
No!
Stop it. no!
(GUNSHOT)
(MEN SHOUT)
Porter.
Josette.
Phone?
Shit.
Who were those men?
Why does it matter to you?
They're Tsotsis. Bandits.
If they find the bodies
it will be very bad for us.
You're gonna have to bury them.
Lord. though they be sinners.
please find it in your heart
to forgive these men.
And grant them eternal rest
in your kingdom.
Amen.
What was that for?
For finding killing so easy.
Here.
Look. I'm sorry if we scared you.
I'm sorry. too.
I owe you thanks for saving Josette
But you must go now.
Come with us. You and the children.
It's not safe here.
Are you mad?
We can't leave.
Why not?
Because she just said they can't.
The Tsotsis have a camp
just across the river. If we leave -
What?
These men.
They smuggle people
into South Africa.
They use our orphanage as
a place for refugees to meet.
They promise papers. passports
and they hand over money.
I don't know what happens to them
when they leave here.
Come with us.
When Sister Carmel and Sister Mary
refused to help these men.
they shot them.
Now they always take
two children as hostages.
to make certain we co-operate.
My burden is to care for those
I can.
And my burden is to get you
and you alone across the border.
Not traipse over the hills
like some cock-eyed Von Trapp family.
Do you know what this place is?
We've got
the Elite Guard hunting us down.
These kids are Aids orphans.
All they've ever known
is loss and abuse.
Anyone who's ever cared for them
is dead. Porter!
Look. it's only. what. three
or four klicks to the Tsotsi camp?
We could get there. rescue the kids.
be back before sunset. No.
Head off under cover of night. be
over the border before daybreak. No.
It'll take Tshuma that long
to pick up on our trail.
No. this is not my problem.
Oh. right. right. Just ignore it.
At least I know why I fight.
you prick! Do you?
I'm not leaving here
without these kids.
What are you gonna do. huh?
Shoot me?
You bastard.
I'll get the rest of the stuff.
You're not going anywhere.
I'll be faster on my own.
Protect the farm.
get the kids packed.
If I'm not be back before sunset
leave without me.
I've seen a lot of killing.
Mr Porter.
Most men seem
to take pleasure in it.
But you...
..you're like a machine.
I don't know
which frightens me more.
These are for Masuku.
This is for the children.
It's not much but they should eat
as well as they can before we leave.
Are you a good man sent by God.
Mr Porter?
Or evil. not to be trusted?
(SLOW CHOIR MUSIC)
Sister.
Don't you think we should
say a prayer for the Army man?
Of course.
Lord. please protect Mr Porter.
May the angels guide him
to where he's going
and please help him
to deliver our brothers back to us.
Amen.
Oh. my God.
The refugees.
(LAUGHTER / GENERAL CHATTER))
Collinson.
Mr Curtis. Section 20.
Going somewhere?
This is unexpected.
Er. would you like something?
Some tea? Something stronger perhaps
No. thank you.
You speak Shona.
As do you.
Handy for dealing with
the regime in Zimbabwe?
Sometimes you have to talk to people
you find unpleasant. Mr Collinson.
How true.
(GENERAL CHATTER)
(My name's Porter.
Sister Benedict sent me.)
Come on. Up there.
(SHOUTS)
Run!
Move. move!
Get down. go.
(GUNFIRE)
What was it. Curtis? Gambling debts
A penchant for houseboys?
How did Tshuma turn you?
You'll forgive me if this is
a fantasy I don't recognise.
You and Colonel Tshuma.
Harare. four weeks ago.
You seem like good friends.
I'm obliged to form relationships
with Zimbabwean officials.
What is this supposed to prove?
On its own. nothing.
But with this...
We've now found
over six million dollars
paid into your several accounts.
According to your own files.
you recruited Masuku
as a sleeper in 2006.
So when Tshuma suggested
you use him to stage
a fake assassination attempt
everything was already in place.
Relax. Curtis.
You're still of use to us.
I'm here to offer you
a chance of redemption.
All we ask is that
you continue letting Tshuma believe
you're working for him but
in reality you'll be working for us
Your money will of course have to be
impounded by the Exchequer
but think of it as a... a donation
Forgive me.
No!
(GUNSHOT)
Curtis. you fucker!
(GUNFIRE)
Get over the bridge
don't stop running until you find
Sister Bernadette. understand? Go!
(GUNFIRE)
Porter!
Shit.
Don't move. Stay where you are.
I've got you. Go. run.
Go. go. run.
Ah. fuck!
"Little fox."
Sister Bernadette.
Where's Porter?
We need to staunch this.
Shit. I'll get the first aid kit.
Bring some cordite.
Understood.
Lie down.
(GROANS IN PAIN)
This is gonna hurt.
(CRIES OUT IN PAIN)
It's all here.
times. dates. communications.
No wonder they didn't need
to torture Masuku.
Does it prove the
assassination attempt was a set up?
Not with Curtis dead.
All we have here is
a legitimate UK government official
planning a hit on Mugabe
using a former SAS operative.
We can deny it all we like...
but the evidence looks overwhelming.
"Our only hope is if Porter
can get Masuku across that border."
"Any news?"
No word.
OK. Stand by your phone.
I'm gonna have
to clean this mess up.
(GROANS)
Lie still
or you'll open your wound.
What time is it?
Around noon.
Kids are packed ready to go.
We need to get moving.
(GROANS)
Who's that?
Get down.
Go to the children. Keep them quiet.
OK.
Pass me the FM.
Quiet.
(COCKS GUN)
(GUNFIRE)
Did you get him?
Bollocks.
That would have been useful.
Well. excuse me. all over the place.
They'd have radioed
their last position.
How long do you think we've got?
Two hours. Three at best.
Right. we need to get moving.
You need to head for this location.
It's about 12km
from here across the border.
You'll find a camp
and a woman called Layla.
Give her this note.
She'll look after you.
You're not coming with us?
No.
No. if I do I'll put you
and the children in greater danger.
Masuku will be with you.
I don't understand.
Tshuma's hunting us down.
If I stay. I might be able
to hold him off long enough
so you can get
across the border to safety.
I've got the answer to my question.
Mr Porter.
May God protect you.
Sister.
I'm gonna stay.
Look after these kids. yeah?
Where do you think you're going?
You know as well as I do their best
chance is if we both make a stand.
I really wish I'd shot you.
You believe the British
will let me live?
I thought I was paranoid.
Sure. they'll wanna hear
what I have to say but then what?
As long as I'm alive.
I'm a liability.
True.
I'm Matabele. John.
I was born a warrior.
My blood belongs here.
in this red soil.
Anyway. we have an advantage.
What's that?
Tshuma needs us alive.
Great.
OK. We've got the four AKs.
Yeah.
The FM.
Mm-hm.
The shotgun. the Tokarev.
And three grenades.
Four. Where did you get those from?
Off the Tsotsis you dropped
by the river?
Didn't have an RPG on them.
did they?
Bloody hell.
My dad had one of these.
No! So did mine.
Unbelievable. It's full.
Ironic.
All we need now is four wheels
and we're out of here.
(ADDER HISSES)
Backed in a corner. mate.
Know how you feel.
(GUNFIRE)
John Dean.
If that really is your name.
Why don't you just give me Masuku?
Do that and I'll consider
letting you live.
I saw the grave you dug for him.
Dean.
Are you really willing
to die for him now?
Or is that your weakness.
do you have a conscience?
Yeah. I'm all heart.
Oi! Looking for me?
(SHOUTS)
Time to go?
Crap. What?
They've got an RPG.
I thought you said
he wanted us alive?
Can't be right all the time.
What is he playing at?
Fuck!
(EXPLOSION)
Clever bastard.
(SCREAMS / FIRES GUN)
You're actually enjoying this.
aren't you?
(SHOUTS)
Plan?
Take out as many as we can.
Save two rounds.
one for you. one for me.
I better not arrive in Hell
and find out you're not there.
(SOLDIERS SHOUT)
What the fuck is this?
(GUNFIRE)
Friends of yours?
South Africans.
Ceasefire! Cease firing!
You three. Check the house.
John Porter. I presume.
Impressive woman
that Sister Bernadette.
You'll be glad to know
she and the children
arrived safely at our exit camp -
(SHOUTS)
(GUNFIRE)
Dean.
Bastard.
It's Porter. (FIRES GUN)
Where's Masuku?
Drowned. River jump. deep water.
What happened to the body?
No idea.
The current must have taken it.
Are you OK?
I'll live.
Good.
That's for leaving my ass
on the road outside the prison.
John.
We need to talk about Lexi.
"It was meant to be
a really simple operation."
"To remove a tumour."
"There was a...
There was a complication."
"I - I don't really understand
what happened."
Oh. sweet heart.
"(CRIES)"
"I'm sorry."
"I'm just not as used to death
as you are."
"I didn't mean that. I'm sorry."
Yeah. you did.
And you're right.
You hang in there for me. yeah?
Be home soon.
I love you.
"I love you. too."
She can stay with Jenny and me
as long as she needs.
She's my daughter.
Stop putting me in your debt.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Come in. Danni. I'm just -
Sorry to disturb you.
What's on your mind. Layla?
I need to know what happened during
the Bratton extraction in 2003.
Porter!
Where are the other men?
Collinson. wheres Mike and Keith?
Fuck!
They're dead!
Porter! Porter!
Why do you want to know?
Because I need to trust
the people my life depends on.
There's a history
between you and Collinson. Secrets.
And at this point in time
I don't trust either of you.
Tell me. John.
What happened in that stairwell?
(SHOUTS)
(CRIES OUT IN PAIN)
IMS Subtitles
Sync by georgel24
www.addic7ed.com